A Guide to the Records of the Virginia State Board of Elections, Central Registration Roster System Reports: Elections Results, 2000-2006
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Virginia State Board of Elections, Central Registration Roster System Reports: Election Results 2000-2006
The Library of Virginia
44899
14 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Virginia State Board of Elections, Client Services, Andrea Morgan-Keeles, 1100 Bank Street, Richmond, VA 23216, transferred 14 April 2010 and accessioned 16 April 2010.
Historical Information
The State Board of Elections was created by an act of the General Assembly passed on March 26 1946. The act granted the board supervisory powers earlier exercised by the secretary of the commonwealth and the Board of State Canvassers over elections. The primary functions of the State Board of Elections are to supervise and coordinate the work of county and city electoral boards and of registrars to obtain uniformity in election proceedings and legality in all elections.
The State Board of Elections consists of three members who are appointed by the Governor subject to confirmation by the General Assembly. A majority of the Board is appointed from the political party which cast the highest number of votes in the Commonwealth for Governor at the last preceding gubernatorial election. The regular term of office is four years, and no member of the Board except the secretary is eligible for more than two successive terms.
The Board issues rules and regulations to guide the work of the electoral boards and registrars. The Board is empowered to remove from office any election official who fails to discharge the duties of his office, and it may request assistance from the office of the Attorney General to enforce election laws or prosecute any violations.
The Board is also responsible for establishing and maintaining a central record-keeping system to provide a roster of all qualified voters in the Commonwealth by county or city and by the precincts within each county or city. The roster must be purged regularly to delete the names of disqualified voters.
Scope and Content
This collection documents election results reports from February 2000 through November 2006 generated by the Virginia Election and Registration System (VERIS), the statewide voter registration system, for all general, primary, and special elections for offices and issues certified by the State Board of Elections. These records consist of statistical reports and include information on voter turnout, county and precint turnout and the percentage of voters who participated by age group. These records do not include final candidate vote totals. The records are arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Presidential Primary, February 2000 (Box 1)
- Muncipal Elections, May 2000 (Box 1)
- General Election, November 2000 (Box 2)
- Special Election 4th Congressional District, June 2001 (Box 2)
- Special Election Senate of Virginia, 25th District, December 2001 (Box 2)
- Northampton County Treasurer, April 2001 (Box 4)
- Democratic Primary, June 2001 (part one) (Box 3)
- Democratic Primary, June 2001 (part two) (Box 4)
- General Election, November 2001 (Box 3)
- Municipal Elections - Cities and Towns, May 2002 (Box 4)
- Special Election, Virginia Senate, 37th District, August 2002 (Box 4)
- Special Election, Virginia House of Delegates, 89th District, August 2002 (Box 4)
- General Election, November 2002 (part one) (Box 4)
- General Election, November 2002 (part two) (Box 5)
- Special Election, Virginia House of Delegates, 40th District, December 2002 (Box 4)
- Greene County School Bond Referendum, February 2003 (Box 6)
- Arlington County Board Vacancy, March 2003 (Box 6)
- Democratic Primary, June 2003 (Box 6)
- Republican Primary, June 2003 (Box 6)
- General Election, November 2003 (part one) (Box 6)
- General Election, November 2003 (part two) (Box 7)
- Democratic Presidential Primary, February 2004 (part one) (Box 8)
- Democratic Presidential Primary, February 2004 (part two) (Box 9)
- Municipal Elections, May 2004 (Box 7)
- Congressional Democratic Primary, June 2004 (Box 7)
- General Election, November 2004 (part one) (Box 7)
- General Election, November 2004 (part two) (Box 8)
- Special Election, House of Delegates, 63rd District, March 2005 (Box 9)
- Fauquier County Bond Referendum, March 2005 (Box 9)
- Henrico County Bond Referendum, March 2005 (Box 9)
- Municipal Election, Town of Vienna, May 2005 (Box 9)
- Republican Primary, June 2005 (part one) (Box 9)
- Republican Primary, June 2005 (part two) (Box 10)
- Democratic Primary, June 2005 (part one) (Box 11)
- Democratic Primary, June 2005 (part two) (Box 8)
- General Election, November 2005 (part one) (Box 12)
- General Election, November 2005 (part two) (Box 10)
- Municipal Elections, May 2006 (part one) (Box 12)
- Municipal Elections, May 2006 (part two) (Box 14)
- Democratic Primary, June 2006 (part one) (Box 12)
- Democratic Primary, June 2006 (part two) (Box 13)
- Republican Primary, June 2006 (Box 14)
- General Election, November 2006 (part one) (Box 14)
- General Election, November 2006 (part two) (Box 13)
- Special Elections: Virginia Senate, 4th District; Virginia House of Delegates, 3, 23, 33 and 97 Districts, 2006 (Box 14)